今回はレストランでの注文にまつわる表現を
さらにレベルアップさせていきましょう
何々は食後にします
この料理には何々がついていますか?
など表現できるようになりましょう。
And again, today's lesson will be in almost all English.
ほぼオールイングして頑張りましょう。
Let's begin with our first time trial.
S-P-R Training
I'll say something in Japanese and you express it in English.
Here's the first one.
メニューをどうぞ。
Say it in English.
Go ahead.
Good.
Okay, here's the next one.
First, how do you say
本日のおすすめ?
in English?
The answer is
Today's specials.
Okay.
Use today's specials to say this.
本日のおすすめは
アチラのボードに書いてあります。
Today's specials are...
Go ahead.
Here's the next one.
私はこのアイロランドの朝食がおすすめです。
a la carte today to monster no got a system a this
okay let's go to the next one first how do you say
sick got this car in English the answer is
might as well but to make a sentence
you need a subject
I,もしくは we, might as well, something.
So, let's use I might as well to say this.
せっかくですから、このアイルランド料理を食べてみます。
Alright, next, let's say this.
たまごはどのようにしますか?
Let's go to the next phrase.
And first, how do you say medamayaki in English?
Medamayaki is sunny side up.
So, use that to say this.
Medamayaki ni shite moratte ii desu ka?
Next one.
First, let's say torizara in English.
The answer is extra plate.
これがわかりやすいです。
All right, use that to say this.
鶏皿をいただけますか?
この料理には飲み物がついています。
コーヒーは食後にします。
Just use after the meal.
Go ahead.
せっかくですからデザートを注文しましょう。
OK, time's up.
How did you do? Did you try to say each one?
Now, Jenny and I will show you the sample answers and give you some advice.
So listen closely.
Menu wo douzo.
Here's a menu.
Honjitsu no susume wa achira no boardo ni kaite arimasu.
Today's specials are written on that board.
私はこのアイロランドの朝食がおすすめです。
I like this Irish breakfast.
You can also use I recommend 〜
But sometimes I like is useful.
私自身の好みで言うならというニュアンスもありますから便利です。
しかし言い方があります。
The intonation is I like something.
私はアラカルトで注文するのがおすすめです。
I like to order a la carte.
せっかくですから、このアイルランド料理を食べてみます。
I might as well try this Irish dish.
卵はどのようにしますか?
How would you like your eggs?
目玉焼きにしてもらっていいですか?
May I have my eggs sunny side up?
鶏皿をいただけますか?
May I have an extra plate?
この料理には飲み物がついています。
This dish comes with a drink.
何々がついてる。
At a restaurant, it's usually something comes with something.
This dish comes with a drink.
Ga kaitou desu.
Okay, here's the next one.
Kouhii wa shokugo ni shimasu.
I'll have a coffee after the meal.
Sekkaku desu kara, deserto wo chumonshimashou.
We might as well order dessert.
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
All right, now it's your turn to try them one more time.
This is your chance to do a little better than before.
Okay, let's go.
Menu wo douzo.
Here's a menu.
Honjitsu no susume wa achira no boudo ni kaite arimasu.
Today's specials are written on that board.
私はこのアイルランドの朝食がおすすめです。
I like this Irish breakfast.
私はアラカルトで注文するのがおすすめです。
I like to order a la carte.
せっかくですから、このアイルランド料理を食べてみます。
I might as well try this Irish dish.
たまごはどのようにしますか?
How would you like your eggs?
目玉焼きにしてもらっていいですか?
May I have my eggs sunny side up?
鶏皿をいただけますか?
May I have an extra plate?
この料理には飲み物がついています。
This dish comes with a drink.
Kōhī wa shokugo ni shimasu.
I'll have a coffee after the meal.
Sekkaku desu kara, dezāto o chūmon shimashou.
We might as well order dessert.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
Okay, today we talked about food and ordering.
Good job.
So, everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.